

PROFILE

I am a skilled and experienced software engineer with seven years of professional experience in the field. Throughout my career, I have had the opportunity to work on various technologies and projects, ranging from game development to website creation and the development of WPF and MAUI applications. As a senior engineer, I have not only contributed to the technical aspects of my work but also taken on leadership responsibilities, including managing teams and effectively communicating with both colleagues and clients to ensure that project requirements are met

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91-9953086237

E-MAIL:

himanshugupta159@gmail.com

WEBSITE:

https://unfragilecoding.blogspot.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/himanshugupta13/

PORTFOLIO:

https://himanshu-gupta159.github.io

SOFT SKILLS

- Time and Resource Management
- Creative Thinker
- Initiative Taker
- Perseverance
- Expressive
- Project and File management
- Team and Client Handling

HIMANSHU GUPTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ticketmaster-Engineer 3 | | 3D Tech | |

May 2022-Present

Kompanions - Educational Games for Kids– Unity Developer

May 2021 - April 2022

Advantal Technologies-Subject Matter Expert-Unity Technologies

April 2020 - April 2021

Splat Studio-Unity Interactive Developer

December 2019-February 2020

Ananta Games – Unity Developer

January 2018 - Sept 2019

Responsibilities:

- Led and managed teams, guiding projects from concept to product delivery while ensuring alignment with client requirements and stakeholder expectations.
- Conducted client meetings and presentations to showcase project progress and gather feedback for continuous improvement.
- Trained and mentored team members on best practices and new technologies, fostering a collaborative learning environment.
- Demonstrated a strong understanding of OOP principles and the software development life cycle (SDLC).
- Utilized proficiency in multiple programming languages, including C#, C++, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, and Python, to deliver versatile solutions.
- Adapted quickly to new technologies and frameworks, as per the business needs and requirements.
- Managed project tasks using Agile methodologies and tools such as Asana, JIRA, and Trello to maintain transparency and efficiency.
- Worked effectively as both a team player and an independent contributor, balancing collaboration with individual responsibilities.
- Worked on large codebases with strong version control practices, utilizing Git for efficient source code management.
- Developed and integrated RESTful APIs.
- Work with Unity Engine to develop high-quality 2D/3D games.
- Designing, creating, implementing, debugging, and refining gameplay features and game mechanics. Design, build, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable code.
- Integration of Art assets, animations, audio, etc.
- Collaborating with other departments to improve overall product.

Projects:

• <u>SaaS</u>: Developed a SaaS that supports designing 2d graphics and mesh using .NET WPF over a 3d software, which helped organization in production cycle and is used by 200+ users for developing graphics within organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JSON,SQL
- Visual Studios IDE
- .NET: ASP,WPF
- C#, C++
- Gaming Engines: Unity, Unreal
- PlayFab
- Photon(multiplayer & chat)
- Goggle IAP
- Git: Gitlb, GitHub, SourceTree
- Scrum: JIRA, Asana, Trello
- Vuforia
- Postman (Rest API)

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application (MCA) Bharati Vidyapeeth Deemed University, School of Distance Education, New Delhi

August 2016 to July 2019 Passed with 67.71% CPI in the First Division

<u>Bachelor of Computer Application</u> (BCA)

Sirifort College of Computer Technology and Management, Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, New Delhi

August 2013 to July 2016
Passed with 71.57 CPI in the First Division

<u>Commerce with Information Practice</u> (+2 CBSE)

Abhinav Public School, Pitampura, New Delhi

July 2011 to May 2013 Passed with 73%

Matriculation (CBSE 10th)

Dayanand public school, Model Town, New Delhi

April 1999 to May 2011 Passed with 6.4 CGPA

- <u>Unreal Plugins:</u> Developed custom tools and plugins in
 Unreal Engine to enhance production pipelines, utilizing
 C++ and Blueprint. Automated various features to minimize
 manual tasks, increasing efficiency and reducing workload
 for the development team. Implemented solutions that
 improved workflow consistency and accelerated project
 timelines.
- <u>CnCre8</u>: Custom exterior structure designing app, to extend your living space.
- <u>TellaTello</u>: A story-based game with a story board to choose from multiply stories and a feature to twist the story anytime by changing Cast behavior through Al in multiplayer mode.

Video Link: Tella Tello

- <u>Tejas (AR)</u>: Created an app to detect any Tejas image/Real Object and instantiate a 3D model over it with some in app features.
- **Spin the wheel**: Created an iPhone game in which user can customize from 3 to 12 option wheel to try his daily luck by spinning the wheel.
- <u>Train Simulation</u>: Created a train game where we achieved a real time train mechanism with a shooting turret to destroy in coming enemy vehicles.

 Video Link: Train Simulation

.NET Experience:

- JSON/XML data conversion to objects.
- WPF, ASP, Xamarin.
- Patterns: MVVM, MAUI

Unreal Engine Experience:

- Implemented rendering workflows using MoviePipelineQueue to enhance cinematic production quality.
- Developed custom plugins in C++ and Blueprint to extend Unreal Engine editor functionalities.
- Designed and implemented intuitive user interfaces to improve user experience within the editor.

Unity Engine Experience:

- Level Design, Game Inputs, UI Dynamic Designing, UI Transitions, Designing Custom Inspector.
- AR (Image Detection, Object Detection)
- Knowledge of Asset bundling to maintain real-time assets download.
- Knowledge of components:
 - o Physics (Collider, Rigidbody, joints)
 - o Navigation (Navmesh, custom waypoint), flocking system.
- Web Services and SDK's:
 - Playfab (Rest API/Cloud Scripting, Game Economy/Virtual currency/Goods, Player Inventory, Leaderboard)
 - o Photon (For chat, multiplayer gaming)
 - o Git (GitHub, BitBucket)
 - o Vuforia (AR)
- Experience with shader graph using URP and HDRP (Dissolve, HoloGram, Cartoon Water, Rain DropRipple).
- Experience building custom inspector and editor for improving game development process.
- Experience with AR, VR using technology like Holo lens, oculus, orbeca, kinect for motion tracking, vuforia, AR kit and AR foundation.
- Knowledge of lightning concepts like prebaked, real time, volumetric, Subsurface scattering and probes.